Marion Nestle Papers, 1970-2017 MSS.159
Fales Library and Special Collections
- Series XI: Media
  - Subseries B: Audio
    - Dr. David Katz + Marion Nestle FNCE Presentation, October 2000; ID: 159.0108 (Box 106, Media ID: 159.0108)
      Original format: Cassette.
    - Dr. Jocelyn Harris talks with Dr. Marion Nestle about (1) Nutrition (2) Women in Medicine (3) Nutrition and Sport, October 9, 1983; ID: 159.0109 (Box 106, Media ID: 159.0109)
    - The Food Programme, undated; ID: 159.0110 (Box 106, Media ID: 159.0110)
    - Leonard Lopate, January 18, 2005; ID: 159.0111 (Box 106, Media ID: 159.0111)
    - Leonard Lopate: Ruth Reichl - Subject: American Food, May 4, 2004; ID: 159.0112 (Box 106, Media ID: 159.0112)
    - Marion Nestle Interview with Mark Hegsted - Westwood, MA, September 7, 2005; ID: 159.0113 (Box 106, Media ID: 159.0113)
    - Marion Nestle & Ruth Reichl: Leonard Lopate, May 2, 2006; ID: 159.0114 (Box 106, Media ID: 159.0114)
    - Prevention 89 Atlanta, GA: US Food and Nutrition Policy Marion Nestle, April 13-16, 1989; ID: 159.0115 (Box 106, Media ID: 159.0115)
    - Prevention 89 Atlanta, GA: US Food and Nutrition Policy Marion Nestle, April 13-16, 1989; ID: 159.0116 (Box 106, Media ID: 159.0116)
    - Towards a Healthy Population: Breaking the Barriers - David Katz, MD, MPH; Marion Nestle, PhD, MPH, 2000; ID: 159.0117 (Box 106, Media ID: 159.0117)
    - The Vegetable Chronicles: The New Role of Diet in Protecting Your Health Tape 1, undated; ID: 159.0118 (Box 106, Media ID: 159.0118)
    - The Vegetable Chronicles: The New Role of Diet in Protecting Your Health Tape 2, undated; ID: 159.0119 (Box 106, Media ID: 159.0119)
    - Vitamania, 2000; ID: 159.0120 (Box 106, Media ID: 159.0120)
    - Conceive On Air with Host Kim Han: Professor Marion Nestle, July 18, 2007; ID: 159.0121 (Box 106, Media ID: 159.0121)
      Original format: CD.
    - Food Fight: When Did Eating Get Controversial? Los Angeles Festival of Books, April 28-29, 2007; ID: 159.0122 (Box 106, Media ID: 159.0122)
    - "FM" 102.7 WNEW: Marion Nestle, March 21, 2004; ID: 159.0123 (Box 106, Media ID: 159.0123)
    - Lighten Up!, July 18, 2003; ID: 159.0124 (Box 106, Media ID: 159.0124)
    - Marion Nestle + Kim Himm: Radio New Zealand, December 6, 2004; ID: 159.0125 (Box 106, Media ID: 159.0125)
    - Marion Nestle & Malden Nesheim: "Feed Your Pet Right" - The Diane Rehm Show, May 12, 2010; ID: 159.0134 (Box 106, Media ID: 159.0134)
    - The People's Pharmacy with Joe & Terry Graedon: Program 588 What to Eat, June 3, 2006; ID: 159.0126 (Box 106, Media ID: 159.0126)
    - Prime Time Radio, June 27, 2006; ID: 159.0127 (Box 106, Media ID: 159.0127)
    - The Splendid Table - Marion Nestle: Who Is Responsible for Our Food?, June 8, 2007; ID: 159.0128 (Box 106, Media ID: 159.0128)
    - The Splendid Table - Marion Nestle: Rose Wines, Vietnamese Grilling, "Birth of a Salesman", August 25, 2006; ID: 159.0129 (Box 106, Media ID: 159.0129)
    - Top 10 Fitness Mistakes: How to Eliminate Failure to Achieve Your Health and Fitness Goals, 2006; ID: 159.0130 (Box 106, Media ID: 159.0130)
    - WOR-AM Joey Reynolds, June 7, 2006; ID: 159.0131 (Box 106, Media ID: 159.0131)
      Duration: 00:50:00
    - Interview by Ruth Reichl of MFK Fisher, 1980-01-03; 2017-08; cuid5947 (Box 106, Media cuid5947, E-records fales_MSS159, E-records cuid5947)
      Original Format: 1/8" audiocassette, Duration: 1 hr. 33 min.
  - Subseries C: Miscellaneous Discs
    Material is arranged alphabetically.
    Born-digital materials have not been preserved and may not be available to researchers.
    - The Partnership for Food Safety Education: FightBAC! Clean. Separate. Cook. Chill., undated; 159.0135 (Box 106, Media 159.0135)
      Original format: Mini Disc.
    - World Economic Forum Annual Meeting 2005: Taking Responsibility for Tough Choices, January 26-30, 2005; ID: 159.0136 (Box 106, Media ID: 159.0136)
    - [Untitled Disc], undated; 159.0137 (Box 106, Media 159.0137)
    - [Untitled Disc], undated; 159.0138 (Box 106, Media 159.0138)
  - Subseries D: Media Paper Documentation
    Material is arranged in order of the ID number that it corresponds to in Media.
    - Paper Documentation from Media ID: 159.0012, undated (Box 107, Folder 1)
    - Paper Documentation from Media ID: 159.0013, April 8, 2004 (Box 107, Folder 2)
    - Paper Documentation from Media ID: 159.0018, September 17, 2004 (Box 107, Folder 3)
    - Paper Documentation from Media ID: 159.0025, September 20, 2005 (Box 107, Folder 4)
    - Paper Documentation from Media ID: 159.0028, May 10, 2002 (Box 107, Folder 5)
    - Paper Documentation from Media ID: 159.0033, April 1, 2004 (Box 107, Folder 6)
    - Paper Documentation from Media ID: 159.0035, June 13, 1992 (Box 107, Folder 7)
    - Paper Documentation from Media ID: 159.0059, May 14, 2006 (Box 107, Folder 8)
    - Paper Documentation from Media ID: 159.0068, April 1, 2009 (Box 107, Folder 9)
    - Paper Documentation from Media ID: 159.0072, March 11, 2008; undated (Box 107, Folder 10)
    - Paper Documentation from Media ID: 159.0076, 2009 (Box 107, Folder 11)
    - Paper Documentation from Media ID: 159.0086, January 19, 2010 (Box 107, Folder 12)
    - Paper Documentation from Media ID: 159.0091, April 30, 2009 (Box 107, Folder 13)
    - Paper Documentation from Media ID: 159.0101, May 1, 2006 (Box 107, Folder 14)
    - Paper Documentation from Media ID: 159.0107, undated (Box 107, Folder 15)
    - Paper Documentation from Media ID: 159.0120, undated (Box 107, Folder 16)
    - Paper Documentation from Media ID: 159.0126, undated (Box 107, Folder 17)
    - Paper Documentation from Media ID: 159.3.0005, February 22, 2005 (Box 107, Folder 18)
- Series XII: Data Storage
  Series XII: Data Storage contains various CDs and floppy disks of Marion Nestle's containing computer files.
  - Ads + Articles: All-Pets Magazine, 1934-1965 (Box 108, Disk ID: 159.3.0001)
  - BioVision 2003: The World Life Sciences Forum Encyclopedia CD 1 (Box 108, Disk ID: 159.3.0002)
  - BioVision 2003: The World Life Sciences Forum Encyclopedia CD 2 (Box 108, Disk ID: 159.3.0003)
  - BioVision 2003: The World Life Sciences Forum Encyclopedia CD 3 (Box 108, Disk ID: 159.3.0004)
  - Hungry Planet: What the World Eats Photo Layout as of February 2005 (Box 108, Disk ID: 159.3.0005)
  - Marion Nestle: Food Politics Photo CD, March 24, 2010 (Box 108, Disk ID: 159.3.0006)
  - NABC Report 17: Governmental Regulations - Agricultural Biotechnology: Beyond Food and Energy to Health and the Environment, undated (Box 108, Disk ID: 159.3.0007)
  - Nestle Index, undated (Box 108, Disk ID: 159.3.0008)
    Original format: floppy disk.
  - Nestle Mauritius, undated (Box 108, Disk ID: 159.3.0009)
  - Norway Photos Marion 1, 2004 (Box 108, Disk ID: 159.3.0010)
  - Norway Photos Marion [2], 2004 (Box 108, Disk ID: 159.3.0011)
  - NUHEMP: Nourishing Pets Inside & Out, undated (Box 108, Disk ID: 159.3.0012)
  - Office of Disease Prevention and Health Promotion: Healthy People 2010 Publications and Other Documents (Box 108, Disk ID: 159.3.0013)
- Series XIII: Objects
  Series XIII: Objects consists of awards Marion Nestle won and is majority plaques.
  - Awards, 1994-2009 (Box 109)
- Series XIV: Oversize
  Series XIV: Oversize contains oversize materials collected by Marion Nestle including posters, newspapers, awards, and a children's cutting board.
  - Milling and Baking News, 1992 (Box 110, Folder 1)
  - [New York Times Image of Men Guarding U.S. Aid Used in Safe Food], 2001 (Box 110, Folder 2)
  - James Beard Foundation Awards, 2003; 2007 (Box 110, Folder 3)
  - Steinhardt Daniel E. Griffiths Research Award, 2004 (Box 110, Folder 4)
  - 2007 Calendar (Folder 13)
  - [Hewbrew Newspaper], 2007 (Box 110, Folder 5)
  - [Printed Newspaper from Hebrew Newspaper], 2007 (Box 110, Folder 6)
  - Slow Food U.S.A. Poster, 2008 (Box 110, Folder 7)
  - Chez Panisse Foundation Poster + Letter, 2010 (Box 110, Folder 8)
  - Wonder Board [Children's Cutting Board], 2011 (Box 110, Folder 9)
  - [Portuguese Nutrition Poster], undated (Box 110, Folder 10)
  - Fun Yum Friends Poster, undated (Box 110, Folder 11)
- Series XV: 2016 Accretion
  Scope and Contents
  This series consists of materials created and collected by Marion Nestle documenting her career in nutrition and public health research and advocacy roughly between the years of 2013-2016. Materials include correspondence, publications, cookbooks or other recipe collections, ephemera for conferences and other events, lecture notes, and press clippings on subjects such as nutrition, public health, and sustainable agriculture. This series also includes materials concerning the research and publication of Nestle's 2015 publication Soda Politics: Taking on Big Soda (And Winning).
  - Correspondence, 2015 (Box 111, Folder 1-2)
  - Lectures, 2015 (Box 111, Folder 3-6)
  - Press Clippings, 2015 (Box 111, Folder 7-13)
  - Business Cards, 2015 (Box 111, Folder 14-16)
  - Soda Politics: Proofs, 2015 (Box 111, Folder 17-19)
  - Soda Politics: Reading Copy, 2015 (Box 111, Folder 20)
  - Promotional Literature and Annual Reports, 2015 (Box 111, Folder 21-22)
  - Conference Materials, 2015 (Box 111, Folder 23)
  - Snacks: Adventures in Food, Aisle by Aisle by Marcy Smothers, 2013 (Box 111, Folder 24)
  - Critical Public Health, June 2015 (Box 111, Folder 25)
  - Scientific American, Summer 2015 (Box 111, Folder 26)
  - Zora Neale Hurston on Florida Food by Fred Opie, 2015 (Box 111, Folder 27)
  - Oversize Signs and Posters, 2015 (Box 110)
- Series XVI: 2017 Accretion
  This accretion consists of materials created and collected by Marion Nestle documenting her career in nutrition and public health research and advocacy roughly between the years of 2014-2017. Materials include correspondence, publications, cookbooks or other recipe collections, ephemera for conferences and other events, lecture notes, and press clippings on subjects such as nutrition, public health, and sustainable agriculture.
  - Appointment Books, 2014-2015 (Box 112, Folder 1-2)
  - Lectures, 2015-2016 (Box 112, Folder 3-5)
  - Press Clippings, 2016 (Box 112, Folder 6)
  - Cookbooks, 2016 (Box 112, Folder 7-8)
  - Promotional Literature and Annual Reports, 2016 (Box 112, Folder 9-13)
  - Conference Materials, 2014-2017 (Box 112, Folder 14-18)
  - Publications, 2016 (Box 112, Folder 19-21)
  - Cartoons about Soda, circa 2000-2017 (Box 112, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence, 2016 (Box 112, Folder 23-24)
  - Media for Food Politics, 2016 (Box 112, Folder 25)
  - Events, 2016 (Box 113, Folder 1-2)
  - Food-related Ephemera, 2016 (Box 113, Folder 3-5)
- Series XVII. 2018 Accretion, 2011-2017
  This accretion consists of materials created and collected by Marion Nestle documenting her career in nutrition and public health research and advocacy roughly between the years of 2011-2017. Materials include correspondence, publications, cookbooks or other recipe collections, ephemera for conferences and other events, lecture notes, and press clippings on subjects such as nutrition, public health, and sustainable agriculture.
  This series has not been arranged by an archivist. The materials are arranged in the order in which they were received from the donor.
  - Appointment Book, 2011 (Box 114, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 2017 (Box 114, Folder 2-3)
  - Food-related Ephemera, 2017 (Box 114, Folder 4-7)
  - Lectures, 2016-2017 (Box 114, Folder 8-10)
  - Media, 2017 (Box 114, Folder 11)
  - The Nation Special Food Issue, 2017-10 (Box 114, Folder 12)
  - Nestle Research, 2017 (Box 114, Folder 13)
  - Press Clippings, 2017 (Box 114, Folder 14)
  - Publications, 2011-2017 (Box 114, Folder 15-19)
  - Rethinking School Lunch: Cooking with California Food, 2011 (Box 115)
  - Flyer, 2016 (Box 110, Folder 12)
- Series XVIII: Archived Websites, December 2011-ongoing; 3 websites in 3 archived websites.
  Food Politics is the blog of Marion Nestle, a New York University Professor of Nutrition, Food Studies, and Public Health. The blog features posts about the global food industry, the impact of food lobbies on industry regulation, and food in popular culture. The blog also features information about Nestle's books and other publications and their press coverage, as well as a calendar of her public appearances and contributions to podcasts and broadcast media.
  This series also includes an interview with Marion Nestle with Jane Hutcheon on Australian Broadcasting Corporation (ABC).
  Accruals
  New site crawls are accrued quarterly.
  Due to technical or privacy issues, archived websites may not be exact copies of the original website at the time of the web crawl. Certain file types will not be captured dependent on how they are embedded in the site. Other parts of websites that the crawler has difficulty capturing includes Javascript, streaming content, database-driven content, and highly interactive content. Full-Text searches of archived websites are available at https://archive-it.org/organizations/567.
  Appraisal
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of www.foodpolitics.com in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.